mackeeper.com 2019-05-07

# Privacy Policy — MacKeeper

Let us clarify the exact meaning of “Personally Identifiable Information” and “Non-Personally Identifiable Information”.

“Personal Data” or “Personally Identifiable Information/Data” (PII) is any data that could potentially identify a specific individual. Any information that can be used to distinguish one person from another can be considered as PII.

“Non-Personally Identifiable Information/Data”, also known as “de-identified” (de-identified data is information that does not actually identify an individual) or “anonymized”, is any information that may correspond to a specific person, account, or profile, but is not sufficient to identify, contact, or locate the person to whom such information pertains. This type of information is frequently used for research, statistical, or aggregation purposes.

#### Personal Information We Collect

We gather the following data from our customers:

Information Provided by You

You will be required to provide your Personal Information at our website or in any other way.

This information is:

  * Login and password;

  * Name;

  * Contact details (such as email address);

  * Communication with MacKeeper Support (via emails, chats or calls).

You can create a MacKeeper account using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you with an option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form.

Information Provided by You will be used only for:

  * Creation of an account;

  * Customer support CRM system;

  * Email communications (read more in the "Email Communications below in this policy);

  * Providing customer support and responding to customer requests;

  * Resolving disputes and protecting our rights, enforcing our policies, and complying with laws.

This data enables fast and efficient rendering of our products and services to our customers. In addition, it is used for communication purposes, such as notifying you about product updates or special offers.

User information is not complemented by information from other sources.

Once you purchase our software, the information collected by our software is linked to your personal information and can be used to handle any technical, product, or customer support requests that you may send to us.

#### Information Collected Automatically

In addition to information you enter yourself, we may collect some information automatically for optimizing your experience when using our product and improving the product itself, including:

  * Device information;

  * User configuration information;

  * IP addresses;

  * Cookies;

  * Browser information.

This data is used for the following purposes:

  * Finding out how many people visit our website and how frequently;

  * Learning how many people use our products and services;

  * Finding out which products and services are used more frequently than others;

  * Collecting some other statistical information.

#### Collecting Information from Children

Company’s website or services are not directed to children. We may not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under 16 years of age.

If you are under 16 years of age, then please do not use or access our product and services at any time or in any manner. Company reserves the right to delete this information if it learns that Personally Identifiable Information of children under the age of 16 has been collected on the services without parental consent. If you are a parent or guardian and discover that your child under the age of 16 has obtained an account on our services, then you may contact our Customer Support at [support@kromtech.net](mailto:support@kromtech.net) and request to delete that child’s personal information.

#### Information collected via ZoomSupport:

  * Audio and/or video recording of a call/session;

  * Static images of your screen, which may be captured during the session only;

  * Chat correspondence;

  * Telephone number (in case of a call);

  * Your personal email;

  * Full name;

  * Mailing address;

  * Password to system (in case of remote fixes);

  * Information about your device, services and software you used.

Collected information is used for:

  * Providing you with remote assistance and other services (learn more about “Remote Access” below in this document);

  * Delivering or installing some programs or assistance tools and software;

  * Analyzing how people use our services, how frequently, which kind of assistance they need, etc. to keep internal analytics;

  * Communication purposes, such as notifying you about product updates or special offers (with your opt-in consent);

  * Personalizing communications with you.

#### ZoomSupport “ZoomDiagnostics”

During the fix session, an Agent may install ZoomSupport “ZoomDiagnostics” on your computer. It is a diagnostic tool that analyzes your computer, gathers basic information about the system properties and settings, and displays it in a comprehensible manner.

This tool can also detect some problems on your computer while working in the background. For example, if something is wrong with the computer system, installed applications, or the memory is full, you may see some notifications with appropriate advice and instructions related to your situation.

We do not collect any Personal Information through this tool. We may collect such information as:

  * OS version;

  * ZD version;

  * Platform;

  * Computer type;

  * Computer name;

  * CPU;

  * RAM;

  * VGA.

#### ZoomSupport “Remote Access”

ZoomSupport “Remote Assistance" offers remote access service to assist us in diagnosing and resolving technical and system issues that appear on your computer. To perform a remote connection, our Agent must receive your prior explicit consent to do so. Explicit consent — also known as express or direct consent — means that an individual is clearly presented with an option to agree or disagree with the collection, use, or disclosure of Personal Information and unambiguously signals his or her agreement.

Additionally, you can terminate the connection at any time. Our Agent will describe to you how to disconnect before the connection is launched.

The entire process allows a “Remote Assistance” Agent to access your device remotely to diagnose any conditions that may interfere with its performance, and either repair it or provide advice on what options are available to fix the issue. By taking advantage of this service, you are giving permission to a “Remote Assistance" Agent to log in to your computer, which may contain your Personal Information, files, documents, etc.

We strongly recommend that you secure your sensitive files before our Agent connects to your computer remotely. Please do not leave these files on your desktop, as it is your responsibility to make your valuable information inaccessible to prevent any type of data loss or corruption. To make your files inaccessible to others, you can use built-in encryption tools on your computer.

Here you can find the step-by-step instructions on how to do so:

  * Mac user - <http://www.hongkiat.com/blog/encrypt-mac-folder/>;

  * Windows user - <http://www.computerhope.com/issues/ch000705.htm>.

In addition, we would like to inform you that even if you do not secure or encrypt your files and they are stored on your desktop, our Remote Assistance Agents will only search your computer in order to identify and correct any conditions on your computer that may hinder its performance and will attempt to limit their interaction with your files to a minimum.

Information collected via MacKeeper™:

  * Email address;

  * IP address;

  * Information about your Mac (Mac OS version, Mac’s model and serial numbers, MAC address, overall system information);

  * Information about your apps (e.g. versions, size, date of last update, etc.);

  * Results of Find & Fix scan.

Collected information is used for:

  * Registration of the MacKeeper account;

  * Proper functioning of MacKeeper™;

  * Supplying you with a list of recommended fixes/software updates.

In case if you want to delete your MacKeeper account, you can do it at your MacKeeper Account settings (read more in the "Privacy Settings" section below in this policy).

#### "Camera Tracking" and "Microphone Tracking"

The Camera and Microphone Tracking feature is designed to detect the usage of camera and microphone (both built-in and external) by other applications on your device. This feature will help you detect unauthorized intrusion into your private life by unknown applications.

When you activate this feature, it will notify you that some application started to use your camera and/or microphone. You can allow your camera and microphone to be always used by applications that you believe are safe, so no notifications will be shown next time for these apps.

MacKeeper does not track and/or save any audio or video recordings, but it indicates the moment when the camera and/or microphone becomes activated by any application that is installed on your device.

#### “Anti-Theft Service”

Anti-Theft is one of security features of MacKeeper™. By default Anti-Theft is disabled. In case you enable Anti-Theft service it will automatically collect your computer's IP address and its geographical position every hour.

You can report your computer STOLEN or LOST on your [MacKeeper](http://account.mackeeper.com/) account, in open Anti-Theft tab. Then it will collect IP address, track location, trace-route and make snapshots using the built-in iSight camera or any external camera every five minutes.

Automatically gathered data collected by the Anti-Theft service is completely anonymous. Therefore even if it is revealed to some third parties, this won’t affect your privacy.

#### “Internet Security”

MacKeeper™ Internet Security feature is powered by Avira’s antivirus engine. In case of installing our Internet Security service, which includes Real Time Safe Browsing, Automatic Security Updates and Real Time Antivirus Scan you confirm that you have read, understood and agreed to Avira [EULA](https://www.avira.com/en/end-user-license-agreement-terms-of-use/) and [Privacy Policy](https://www.avira.com/en/general-privacy/).

#### Email Communications:

You can choose to opt-in to some emails informing you about product features, news, updates, and special offers from us and our partners. You can manage your email communication preferences at your MacKeeper Account.

Please note that we will send you important administrative and transactional messages (e.g. purchase receipts) informing you about temporary or permanent changes to our product and services (e.g. account, security or compliance notifications or alerts).

Occasionally you will receive customer satisfaction surveys via email where you will be asked to provide us with your opinion and some additional personal information. It will be used solely by us for our internal usage to improve our products and services, overall, making your user experience better.

#### Information that is Collected and Provided by Third Parties:

Some of your Personal Information, such as your name, email address and other information (like the type of subscription you bought, it's price, etc.; please note that we don't collect information about your credit card number or other sensitive data), may be collected and provided to us by third parties, such as [cleverbridge©](https://www.cleverbridge.com/corporate/), [PayPro Global©](https://payproglobal.com/) and [RevenueWire®](https://www.revenuewire.com/).

To make your investigation easier, we would like to provide you with the links to third-party policies:

  * [Cleverbridge© Privacy Policy](https://www.cleverbridge.com/corporate/privacy-policy/);

  * [PayPro Global© Privacy Policy](http://docs.payproglobal.com/documents/legal/privacyPolicy.pdf);

  * [RevenueWire® Privacy Policy](https://www.revenuewire.com/privacy-policy/).

In case of ZoomSupport remote assistance, to access to your device remotely, our Remote Assistance Agents use third-party software, such as LogMeIn® and TeamViewer. By accepting the Terms & Conditions and Privacy Policy of our Remote Assistance service, you therefore accept the [Terms & Conditions](https://secure.logmein.com/policies/termsandconditions.aspx) and [Privacy Policy](https://secure.logmein.com/policies/privacy.aspx) of LogMeIn® and [Terms & Conditions](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/eula/) and [Privacy Policy](https://www.teamviewer.com/en/privacy-policy/) of TeamViewer.

Please read all Privacy Policies that are listed above to make sure that you agree to all conditions; otherwise, do not purchase or use our service.

#### Data Retention

We will retain your Personal Information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law. We may keep certain information even after you stop using our services if it is necessary to comply with our legal obligations, meet regulatory requirements, resolve disputes, prevent fraud and abuse, or enforce this agreement.

We may retain your Personal and/or non-Personal Data even after you stop using our services and your account becomes inactive in our system.

We retain this information to protect our Company in disputes and proceedings, to comply with legal obligations, meet regulatory requirements, etc. In addition, if you would like to use our services again in the future, it is easier for us to perform remote assistance when we already know the specifics of your computer and how we have helped you before.

If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact our Customer Support at support@kromtech.net.
